Guide to the Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies records, 1974-1986.
Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies records,
- Webb, Lee. State Bank for Coops: A Proposal to Establish a State Bank for Cooperatives and a State Cooperative Development Agency. Washington D.C.: Institute for Policy Studies, 1975., October 1975; 82; Policy Proposal (Box 1)
  Policy review proposal. 6 sections including cooperative approach to employment & economic development, cooperatives today, opportunities for creation & expansion, history of government efforts, assistance needed, conclusion & recommendations, plus footnotes & bibliography. Proposal prepared for the Department of Employment Development of the State of California
- Jones, David & Webb, Lee (Ed.). America's Cities and Countries: A Citizens Agenda. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983; 83; Policy Agenda (Box 1)
  Book with 11 sections for each policy issues plus list of contributors
- Newman, Sandy & Jones, David with Lizzaralde, Carlos. Model Agenda. Voter Registration: An Agenda for the States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., October 1983; 1; Policy Agenda (Box 2)
  "A model agenda on a critical public policy issue prepared for public officials, civic leaders and activists" - 8 pages
- Freedberg, Michael & Hatfield, Anne. Financing Energy Conservation: What States and Cities Can Do. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983; 2; Policy Report (Box 2)
  4 chapters including public & private sources of funds, financing vehicles, loan structures, plus glossary and resource list
- Jones, David & Webb, Lee (Ed.). America's States: A Citizens Agenda 1983-84. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983-1984; 3; Policy Agenda (Box 2)
  Book with 10 sections for each policy issues plus liste of contributors
- Bohannon, Mark & Buckley, Mary & Osborne, David. The New Right In The States: The Groups, The Issues, And The Strategies. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1984., 1984; 4; Policy Report (Box 2)
  6 sections including what is the new right, its organizations, future directions, challenges, and appendices
- Tryens, Jeffrey (Compiled by). Toxic Substances: New Ideas for the Midwest, Agenda '85. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1984., December 7-8, 1984; 5; Policy Report (Box 2)
  Chicago: various legislations/act compiled with data and other info
- Martin, Sandra. The New Right's Education Agenda for the States: A Legislator's Briefing Book. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., 1985; 6; Policy Brief (Box 2)
  5 chapters including "the alec approach to education", what legislators need to know, "parent's role in education", "teacher's role in education", "state's role in education", plus appendices
- Sherry, Susan. High Tech and Toxics: A Guide for Local Communities. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., October 1985; 7; Policy Guide (Box 2)
  469 page book with 7 chapters including high technology, facing the problem, health hazards, opportunities for local government, etc., plus appendices
- Various authors. Women in the Economy: Equity for Farm Women - Proposals for Estate Tax Reform. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1978., 1978; 8; Policy Report (Box 2)
  Policy report on women farmers which includes policy reviews, reforms and newspaper articles
- Kelly, Ed (Ed.). Tax Abatements - Resources for Public Officials, Trade Unionist & Community Leaders. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1979., 1979; 9; Policy Report (Box 2)
  4 sections including: the problem, war between the states, citizen/labor mobilization, Ohio case study
- 1979 Annual Report: The Agriculture Project. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 10; Annual Report (Box 2)
  6 sections including: history & goals, highlights of project activities, conference & workshops, publications, staff, steering committee, plus appendiz
- Coltman, Edward & Metzenbaum, Shelley. Investing in Ourselves: Strategies for Massachusetts - Studies in Pension Fund Investments 1. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1979., June 1979; 11; Policy Report (Box 2)
  A report of 6 chapters plus appendix A-E including: intro, objectives, alternatives, checklist of actions, investor strategies, resources & proposed legislation
- Redirecting Public Funds: A Strategy for the City of Berkley - Studies in Pension Fund Investments 9. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1980., May 1, 1980; 12; Policy Report (Box 2)
  "A report of the Citizens Committee on Responsible Investments". 8 sections including: intro, summary of recommendations, promoting indirect benefits to Berkley from investments, investment vehicles, cooperation w/ other investors, etc., plus appendices A-H
- Schur, Robert & Phelan, Marilyn. The Housing Crisis: A Strategy for Public Pension Funds - Studies in Pension Fund Investements 11. Washigton D.C.: Conference on Alternatives State & Local Policies, 1981., December 1981; 13; Policy Report (Box 2)
  7 sections including: diagnosis of the problem, pension fund transfusion, treating the patient, alternatives, etc., plus notes
- Rosen, Corey. Employee Ownership: Issues, Resources and Legislation - A Handbook for Employees & Public Officials. Washington D.C.: National Center for Employee Ownership & the Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1982., June 1982; 14; Policy Report (Box 2)
  8 sections including: executive summary, intro, employee ownership models, employee-owned companies, obstacles to expanding employee ownership, federal programs, roles for state & local governments, plus footnotes & appendices
- Freedberg, Louis. America's Poisoned Playgrounds: Children and Toxic Chemicals. Washington D.C.: Youth News & Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983; 15; Policy Report (Box 2)
  8 chapters including: overview & major findings, "Inner City Canaries", pesticides, freeway parks, etc., and resources for action
- Goldberg, Lenny. Building Cooperatives in California: A Model for State Action. California Cooperative Federation and Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983; 16; Policy Report (Box 2)
  4 chapters including: co-op history in CA, consumer goods & services cooperatives, housing cooperatives and worker cooperatives, plus appendix A -D
- Tryens, Jeffrey (Ed.). The Toxics Crisis: What States Should Do. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1983., 1983; 17; Policy Report (Box 2)
  6 sections including: intro, protecting workers, protecting the community, waste disposal waste clean-up, plus list of contributors and end notes
- Tarr-Whelean, Linda (Ed.). A Women's Rights Agenda for the States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1984., 1984; 18; Policy Agenda (Box 2)
  5 sections including: intro, employment & economic issues, human services & education, political & human rights, plus list of contributors
- Webb, Lee & Tryens, Jeffrey (Ed.). An Environmental Agenda for the States. Washigton D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1984., 1984; 19; Policy Agenda (Box 2)
  14 chapters on background facts and legislations for 14 environmental issues, plus intro & list of contributors
- Arnheim, Louise & Tryens, Jeffrey (Ed.). Legislative Sourcebook - Health Policy: Expanding Access to Care. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., 1985; 20; Policy Report (Box 2)
  2 part book: PartI:Funding Mechanism. PartII: Basic Health Care Plans & Insurance Proposals.
- Peters, Farley (Compiled by). Taxes and Revenue: New Ideas for the Midwest - Agenda '85. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1984., December 7-8, 1984; 21; Policy Report (Box 2)
  Chicago Illionois. 5 sections including legislation reviews and newspaper articles around categories of: "fiscal structures and policy considerations", "management and budget policies", "tax and revenue innovations", "tax policy and economic development", and "general"
- Davidoff, Linda & Williams, Cynthia (Prepared by). Executive Orders: A New Strategy to Use Public Agencies to Increase Voter Registration. Washington D.C.: Human Serve Fund, Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., 1985; 22; Policy Report (Box 2)
  6 sections including intro, executive order strategy, texts of executive orders, implementation instructions to employees, key issues and list of contacts
- Arnheim, Louise & Webb, Lee (Ed.). A Health Care Agenda for the States. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., 1985; 23; Policy Report (Box 2)
  7 sections including: intro, the health care crisis, health care for the elderly, health care financing & delivery, health care services, new approaches, health protection and list of contributors. (Note: Cover falling off)
- Webb, Lee (Compiled by). Bank Deregulation: New Ideas for Illinois. Springfield, Illinois. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1985., April 10, 1985; 24; Policy Report (Box 2)
  Newspaper articles & policy reviews on the categories of "general", "consumers", "economic development", and "communities"
- Dawson, Steven L.. Worker Cooperatives and the National Consumer Cooperative Bank Act. Washington D.C.: Conference/Alternative State & Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 25; Policy Report (Box 2)
  Paper concept on worker cooperatives and the Bank Act - 15 pages
- Parker, Richard & Taylor, Tamsin. Strategic Investment: An Alternative for Public Funds. Studies in Pension Fund Investments 6. Washington D.C: Conference on Alternative & Local Policies, 1979., 1979; 26; Policy Report (Box 2)
  9 sections including changes in the investments climate, the common stock controversy, linked deposits, stategic investment policy, etc.
- Harrington, John C.. Packaging Housing Mortage Loan: Strategies for California. Studies in Pension Fund Investments 2. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative & Local Policies, 1979., September 1979; 27; Policy Report (Box 2)
  5 sections of policy review including retirement & housing fund in CA, major findings, etc., plus appendices & bibliography
- Webb, Lee & Schweke, William (Ed.). Public Employee Pension Funds: New Strategies for Investment. Resources for Public Officials, Trade Unionists & Community Leaders. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1980., 1980; 28; Policy Report (Box 2)
  11 chapters including overview, public control of capital, pension fund investment, political & institutional obstacles, etc., plus glossary & resources
- Belden, Joe & Edwards, Gibby & Guyer, Cynthia & Webb, Lee (Ed.). New Directions in Farm, Land and Food Policies: A Time for State and Local Action. The Agriculture Project. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Policies, 1981., Jaunary 1980; 29; Policy Report (Box 2)
  7 sections including strengthening the family farm, protecting farm land, conserving energy & natural resources, supporting low-income farmers, etc.
- Various authors. Southwest Regional Conference Report. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1975., December 5, 1975; 30; Report (Box 2)
  Pamphlet sent to conference participants. Summarizes the conference discussions, offers articles that apply to the conference.
- Conference Report: Where do we go from here?, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Midwest Conference Alternative State and Local Public Policy Report, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Public Policy Reader of the Conference on Alternative State & Local Public Policies held June 13-15, 1975 in Madison, Wisconsin. The reader was edited and compiled by Derek Shearer and Lee Webb., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  This reader is available online here: http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/29732
- Programs and Proposals: A Reader on Public Policy, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Southwest Regional Conference Report, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- A Conference on Alternative Public Policy for Northeastern Cities, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Legislative Handbook on Women's Issues, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Public Control of Public Money: Should States and Cities Have Their Own Banks?, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Report of the Second Annual Conference on Alternative State and Local Public Policies, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Second Annual Public Policy Reader of the Conference on Alternative State & Local Public Policies held June 10-13, 1976 in Austin, Texas, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  This reader is available online here: http://ecommons.library.cornell.edu/handle/1813/29733
- The Political and Economic Crisis of Northeast Cities, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Industrial Exodus, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Murray, Edward & Webb, Lee (Ed.). New Directions in State & Local Public Policy. Washington D.C.: Conference on Alternative State & Local Public Policies, 1977., June 1977; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Book that "details the innovative legislation and proposals in some of the crucial areas that governments face". 11 chapters on 11 policy issues (taxes, agriculture, controlling corporations, energy, revenue sharing, women in the economy, public employees, public capital, reinvestment, campaigns, & land use)
- New Directions in State and Local Tax Reform, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Public Control of Public Money, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Report of the Third Annual Conference on Alternative State and Local Public Policies, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Fourth Annual National Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Pension Fund Investments: The Issue of Control, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Public Policies for the Eighties, Perspectives and Resources for State and Local Action, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Reforming Public Investment Policies: Proposals for San Diego, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Women in the Economy, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Women in the Economy: Policies and Strategies for Change, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- A Guide to Cooperative Alternatives, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Fifth Annual National Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies: Agenda for the 80's, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Investing in Ourselves: Strategies for Massachussetts, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Misc. notes from Fifth Annual National Conference on Alternative State and Local Policies: Agenda for the 80's, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- New Directions in Farm, Land and Food Policies, A Time for State and Local Action, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Packaging Housing Mortgage Loans: Strategies for California, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Public Employee Pension Funds: New Strategies for Investment, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Strategic Investment: An Alternative for Public Funds, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- The Public Balance Sheet: A New Tool for Evaluating Economic Choices, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- The Shifting Property Tax Burden: The Untold Cause of the Tax Revolt, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Assisting Beginning Farmers: New Programs and Responses, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Cooperatives and Energy #1: New Coops and the National Consumer Coop Bank, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Energy Conservation: Resources, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Investing in Minnesota: A Proposal to use State Moneys for Maximum Benefit, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Manual on Pay Equity: Raising Wages for Women's Work, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Natural Resource Taxation: Perspectives, Resources, and Issues, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- New Initiatives in Energy Legislation: A State by State Guide: 1979-1980, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Plant Closings: Issues, Politics, and Legislation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Redirecting Public Funds: A Strategy for the City of Berkeley, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Revitalizing New York City's Economy: The Role of Public Pension Funds, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Social Investments and the Law: The Case for Alternative Investments, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- State and Local Tax Revolt: New Directions for the 1980s. Author Tips/Webb, 1980; 44 (Box 4)
- The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: Will its Promise be Realized?., 1980; 45 (Box 4)
- The New Right: A Growing Force in State Politics. Author Hunter, William, 1980; 46 (Box 4)
- Citizen Involvement in Community Energy Planning. Author Hughes/Pape, 1981; 47 (Box 4)
- Cooperatives & Energy #2: Annoted Bibliography and Resource Directory., 1981; 48 (Box 4)
- Divesting From South Africa: A Prudents Approach for Pension Funds. Author Litwak/Estrella/ McTique, 1981; 49 (Box 4)
- Employee Ownership: Issues, Resources and Legislation. Author Rosen, Corey, 1981; 50 (Box 4)
- Energy Planning and Education: A Handbook for Community Leaders and Organizations. Author The Energy Project, 1981; 51 (Box 4)
- Housing and Abandonment: Does Rent Control Make a Difference?. Author Marcuse, Peter, 1981; 52 (Box 4)
- Innovative Energy Policies: A Briefing Book. Author The Energy Project, 1981; 53 (Box 4)
- Innovative Energy Projects: Models for Self-Sufficiency. Author Hughes/Pape, 1981; 54 (Box 4)
- Local Alternative Energy Futures: Perspectives and Resources. Author Brasuk/Mode/Glass, 1981; 55 (Box 4)
- Meeting Local Energy Needs: Resources for Self-Sufficiency. Author Freedburg, Michael, 1981; 56 (Box 4)
- Solarizing America: The Davis Experience. Author Vine, Edward, 1981; 57 (Box 4)
- State and Local Solar Energy Policy: Meeting Low-Income Needs. Author Okagaki, Alan, 1981; 58 (Box 4)
- The Housing Crisis: A Strategy for Public Pension Funds. Author Schur/Phelan, 1981; 59 (Box 4)
- The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: The First Year: Analysis of Policies and Recommended Changes. Author Gordan/Logan, 1981; 60 (Box 4)
- Ways & Means - Moved to a different box, May-June 1981; 61 (Box 4)
- Community Energy Cooperatives: How to Organize, Manage and Finance Them., 1982; 62 (Box 4)
- Mandating Social Prudence: A Handbook for Pension Investment. Author Leibig, Michael, 1982; 63 (Box 4)
- New Initiatives in Energy Legislation: A State by State Guide: 1981-1982. Author The Energy Project, 1982; 64 (Box 4)
- Putting America Back to Work: What States and Cities can do. Author Schweke/Webb, 1982; 65 (Box 4)
- The National Consumer Cooperative Bank: Eligibility: How Coops and Community Organizations Can use the Coop Bank., 1982; 66 (Box 4)
- America's Cities and Counties: A Citizen's Agenda., 1983; 67 (Box 4)
- America's Poisoned Playgrounds: Children and Toxic Chemicals. Author Freedburg, Michael, 1983; 68 (Box 4)
- Building Cooperatives in California: A Model for State Action., 1983; 69 (Box 4)
- Financing Energy Conservation: What States and Cities can do. Author Freedburg/Hatfield, 1983; 70 (Box 4)
- Model Agenda: Voter Registration: An Agenda for the States., 1983; 71 (Box 4)
- The Toxics Crisis: What the States Should do. Author Tryens, Jeffrey, 1983; 72 (Box 4)
- America's States: A Citizen's Agenda 1983-1984., 1984; 73 (Box 4)
- An Environmental Agenda for the States. Author Webb/Tryens, 1984; 74 (Box 4)
- Winning the Right to Know: A Handbook for Toxics Activists. Author Chess, Caron, 1984; 75 (Box 4)
- Financing Deregulation: New Opportunities for Rural Economic Development. Author Siegel/Kwass/Reamer, 1986; 76 (Box 4)
- Legislative Sourcebook on the Environment. Author Tryens, Jeffrey, 1986; 77 (Box 4)
- Policy Strategies for an Adequate Family Income: a Briefing Book., 1986; 78 (Box 4)
- State Issues Forum: Policy Strategies for an Adequate Family Income., 1986; 79 (Box 4)
- Business Climate Yields to Growth Climate: The Midwest Pioneers the New Age., 1987; 80 (Box 4)
- The Women's Economic Justice Agenda: Ideas for the States. Author Tarr-Whelan/Isensee, 1987; 81 (Box 4)
- Women's Voices: A Report., 1992; 82 (Box 4)
- Beginning Farmers Assistance Acts (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 83 (Box 4)
- Interstate Grain Marketing Compact (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 84 (Box 4)
- Iowa Family Farm Act (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 85 (Box 4)
- Iowa Non-Resident Alien Ownership Act (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 86 (Box 4)
- Minnesota Family Farm Security Act (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 87 (Box 4)
- New Directions in Farm, Land and Food Policies: A Time for State and Local Action., Unknown; 88 (Box 4)
- North Dakota Graduated Land Tax (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 89 (Box 4)
- Protecting the Family Farm/Preserving Farm Land. Author Webb, Unknown; 90 (Box 4)
- Saskatchewan Land Bank Act (Innovative Legislation Series). Author The Agricultrue Project, Unknown; 91 (Box 4)
- State Wars over Saturn: A Policy Reader on Industrial Recruitment. Author Midwest Leadership Project, Unknown; 92 (Box 4)